A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, S-Z FA394
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Weaver, Warren
  - 1947-1948, Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences (Reel M Wea 1, Frame 8, Box 502-503)
    Norway; Netherlands; Penicillin; Nutrition; Biophysics; Brazil; Agriculture; Biology -- Research; Sweden; Proteins; Venezuela; United States; Mexico; Cytology; Colombia; England; Denmark; France; Enzymes; Guatemala; Genetics
  - Index, 1949; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 17 pages; 1949.
  - 1949, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences; Weaver, Warren (Reel M Wea 1, Frame 9, Box 503)
    The diary documents Rockefeller Foundation's focus on experimental biology and Weaver's tour of Mexico and South America to survey agricultural programs.
    United States; Uruguay; Peru; Radiation; Chile; Botany; Biology -- Research; Argentina; Nutrition; Mexico; Cytology; Colombia; Agriculture; Zoology
  - Index, 1950; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 17 pages; 1950.
  - 1950, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences; Weaver, Warren (Reel M Wea 1, Frame 10, Box 503)
    This diary emphasizes the Division of Natural Sciences focus on life sciences and on projects that increase ma's understanding of himself. Weaver also tours Europe and the agricultural programs in Mexico and South America.
    Biology -- Research; Botany; Chemistry; Colombia; Physics; Agriculture; Astronomy; Belgium; United States; Switzerland; Scotland; Proteins; Zoology; Genetics; France; England; Corn; Mexico; Ireland
  - Index, 1951; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences; Weaver, Warren
    Index; 12 pages; 1951.
  - 1951, Rockefeller Foundation. Natural Sciences and Agriculture; Weaver, Warren (Box 503, Reel M Wea 1, Frame 11)
    The Division of Natural Sciences has reorganized into the Division of Natural Sciences and Agriculture. Weaver interviews various professionals in the field of natural sciences and agriculture. He also visits the Colombian Agricultural Program.
    United States; Colombia; Physics; Chemistry; Biology -- Research; Agriculture
  - Index, 1952; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 13 pages; 1952.
  - 1952, Rockefeller Foundation. Natural Sciences and Agriculture; Weaver, Warren (Box 504, Reel M Wea 3, Frame 12)
    The 1952 diary documents agricultural projects.
    Agriculture; Chemistry; India; Biology -- Research; Botany; Physics; Proteins; Mexico; Pakistan; Turkey; United States
  - Index, 1953; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences; Weaver, Warren
    Index; 15 pages; 1953.
  - 1953, Rockefeller Foundation. Natural Sciences and Agriculture; Weaver, Warren (Box 504, Reel M Wea 4, Frame 13)
    The focus of the 1953 diary is experimental biology and agriculture.
    Chemistry; Burma; Japan; India; Thailand; Philippines; United States; Agriculture; Biology -- Research
  - Index, 1954; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 6 pages; 1954.
  - 1954, Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Weaver, Warren (Box 504, Reel M Wea 4, Frame 14)
    Weaver takes a trip to Europe to tour universities and observe research facilities. Interviews regarding genetic research are documented.
    Sweden; United States; Zoology; Agriculture; Chemistry; Biology -- Research; DNA; Denmark; Genetics; England; Physics; Life sciences; Karolinska Institutet
  - Index, 1955; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 7 pages; 1955.
  - 1955, Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural Sciences and Agriculture; Weaver, Warren (Box 504, Reel M Wea 4, Frame 15)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. Weaver holds discussions with professionals in the fields of natural and agricultural sciences. He takes a trip to East Asia to survey agriculture programs and maize projects.
    United States; Thailand; Plant breeding; Mexico; Japan; Israel; Insecticides; Indonesia; India; France; Cyprus; Corn; Biology -- Research; Agriculture
  - Index, 1956; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 8 pages; 1956.
  - 1956, Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences (Box 505, Reel M Wea 4, Frame 16)
    The 1956 diary documents Weaver's tour of Africa.
    Uganda; South Africa; Nutrition; Nigeria; Malaria; Kenya; Ghana; Genetics; England; Congo; Biology -- Research; Agriculture; Africa; United States
  - Index, 1957; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 8 pages; 1957.
  - 1957, Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences (Box 505, Reel M Wea 5, Frame 17)
    The 1957 diary documents Weaver's trip to Poland.
    Poland; Biology -- Research; United States; Puerto Rico; Agriculture
  - Index, 1958; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 7 pages; 1958.
  - 1958, Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Weaver, Warren (Box 505, Reel M Wea 5, Frame 18)
    Weaver tours poland to survey life sciences education.
    Biology -- Research; Agriculture; Genetics; Education; United States; Poland
  - Index, 1959; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
    Index; 5 pages; 1959.
  - 1959, Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Weaver, Warren (Box 505, Reel M Wea 5, Frame 19)
    This brief diary documents Weaver's last year at the Rockefeller Foundation. it is arranged by interview and visit. He holds conversations with various professionals in the fields of natural and medical sciences.
    Medicine; Biology -- Research
- Weir, John M.
  - 1939-1940 (Box 506)
  - 1947 (Box 506)
  - 1948 (Box 506)
  - 1949 (Box 506)
  - 1950 (Box 506)
  - 1940-1942 (Box 506)
  - 1947 (Box 506)
  - 1948 (Box 506)
  - 1949 (Box 506)
  - 1950 (Box 506)
  - Index (Box 506)
  - 1951 (Box 507)
  - 1951-1953 (Box 507)
  - 1952 January-July (Box 507)
  - 1953 (Box 507)
  - 1954 (Box 507)
  - 1955 January-April (Box 507)
  - 1955 May-August (Box 507)
  - 1955 September-December (Box 508)
  - 1956 January-May (Box 508)
  - 1956 June-July (Box 508)
  - 1956 August-December (Box 508)
  - 1957 January-March (Box 508)
  - 1957 April-July (Box 508)
  - 1957 August-December (Box 508)
  - 1958 January-April (Box 508)
  - 1958 May-October (Box 509)
  - Africa, 1958 November-December (Box 509)
  - Africa, 1958-1959 (Box 509)
  - 1959 January-March (Box 509)
  - 1959 April-June (Box 509)
  - 1959 July-December (Box 509)
  - 1960 January-April (Box 510)
  - 1960 May-July (Box 510)
  - 1960 August-December (Box 510)
  - 1961 January-April (Box 510)
  - 1961 May-July (Box 510)
  - 1961 August-December (Box 510)
  - 1962 January-April (Box 511)
  - 1962 May-December (Box 511)
  - 1963 (Box 511)
  - 1964 (Box 511)
  - 1965 (Box 511)
  - 1966 (Box 512)
  - 1967 (Box 512)
  - 1968 January-May (Box 512)
  - 1968 June-December (Box 512)
  - 1969 January-May (Box 512)
  - 1969 June-December (Box 512)
  - 1970 (Box 512)
  - 1971 January-March (Box 512)
  - 1971 April-December (Box 512)
  - 1972 January-April (Box 512)
  - 1972 April-November (Box 512)
  - Index, 1954-1959 (Box 512)
  - Index, 1960-1969 (Box 512)
- Wellhausen, Edwin J.
  In his four decades with the Rockefeller Foundation (RF) from 1943 to 1983, Edwin Wellhausen played a central role in the Foundation's agricultural work in Mexico and in international agricultural development more broadly. Wellhausen's distinguished career included leading both the Mexican Agricultural Program (MAP) and the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center in Mexico (known by its Spanish acronym, CIMMYT).
  Wellhausen was born on September 10, 1907 in Fairfax, Oklahoma. He earned his B.S. in plant pathology from University of Idaho (1932), and his Ph.D. in genetics and plant breeding from Iowa State University (1936). After completing his doctorate, Wellhausen was a General Education Board Fellow at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research and the Department of Physiology at the University of California, Berkeley, and then worked briefly for Agricultural Experiment Stations at Montana State College and West Virginia University.
  In 1943, Mexican Agricultural Program Local Director (and future RF President) J. George Harrar selected Wellhausen to head the MAP's corn breeding efforts. Because corn was integral to the Mexican diet, his work focused on both boosting corn yields and developing hybrids that would improve Mexico's long-term corn production. After a decade leading the corn breeding program, Wellhausen succeeded Harrar as MAP Local Director, and held the position until 1958.
  Wellhausen worked tirelessly to foster international cooperation toward the improvement of agricultural research and production. From 1959-1963, he was Director of the Inter-American Maize Improvement Program, which led to the establishment in 1963 of the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center in Mexico (CIMMYT), headquartered in Mexico City. Wellhausen served as CIMMYT's first Director General.
  Wellhausen retired in June 1973, but spent the next decade as a Special Field Staff Member working on a variety of RF Latin American assignments. He continued to foster the development of international research institutes, counseled international governments and agricultural institutions, and consulted for the International Agricultural Development Service (IADS). He retired fully from the Rockefeller Foundation in 1983, when the Foundation closed its Mexico field office.
  Over the course of his career, Wellhausen published dozens of articles about corn production, developed more than 60 hybrids and varieties of corn, and trained Latin American agronomists in the breeding and production of the crop. He received several awards and honors from the international community in recognition of his efforts. In 1969, the Mexican government awarded him the Order of the Aztec Eagle, First Class, the highest decoration granted to foreigners.
  Edwin Wellhausen died on January 7, 2001.
  - 1952 (Box 513)
  - 1953 (Box 513)
  - 1954 (Box 513)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 513)
  - 1957 (Box 513)
  - 1958 (Box 513)
  - 1959 (Box 513)
  - 1960-1962 (Box 514)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 514)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 514)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 514)
- Wells, Clifford W.
  - 1939, 1941, 1944-1946 (Box 514)
  - 1947-1949 (Box 515)
- Wernimont, Kenneth W.
  - 1952 (Box 515)
  - 1953 January-August (Box 515)
  - 1953 September-December (Box 515)
  - 1954 January-June (Box 515)
  - 1954 July-December (Box 515)
  - 1955 January-May (Box 516)
  - 1955 June-December (Box 516)
  - 1956 January-July (Box 516)
  - 1956 August-December (Box 516)
  - 1957 January-June (Box 516)
  - 1957 July-September (Box 516)
  - 1957 October-December (Box 516)
  - 1958 January-April (Box 517)
  - 1958 May-August (Box 517)
  - 1958 September-December (Box 517)
  - 1959 January-July (Box 517)
  - 1959 August-September (Box 517)
  - 1959 October-December (Box 517)
  - 1960 January-May (Box 518)
  - 1960 June-August (Box 518)
  - 1960 September-December (Box 518)
  - 1961 January-March (Box 518)
  - 1961 April-July (Box 518)
  - 1961 August-December (Box 518)
  - 1962 Diary (with Index) (Box 518)
  - 1963 (Box 519)
  - 1964 (Box 519)
  - 1965 (Box 519)
  - 1966 (Box 519)
  - 1967 (Box 519)
  - 1968 January-June (Box 519)
  - 1968 July-December Diary (with Index) (Box 519)
  - 1969 January-June (Box 519)
  - 1969 July-December Diary (with Index) (Box 519)
  - 1970 (Box 519)
  - 1971-1972 Diary (with Index) (Box 520)
    See also- Ellsworth T. Neumann, 1973-1976.
  - 1973-1974 Diary (with Index) (Box 520)
- West, Robert L.
  - 1962 January (Box 520)
  - 1962 February (Box 520)
  - 1962 March-April (Box 520)
  - 1962 May-July (Box 520)
  - 1962 August-December (Box 520)
  - 1964 May-December (Box 521)
  - 1964 November (Box 521)
  - 1965 January-August (Box 521)
  - 1965 September-December (Box 521)
  - Interviews, 1965 March-April (Box 521)
  - 1966 January-February (Box 521)
- Williams, Bruce E.
  - 1972-1975 (Box 522)
  - 1976-1986 (Box 522)
- Willits, Joseph H.
  - 1939-1941, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry; 132 pages (Reel M Wil 1, Frame 1, Box 523)
    Organized according to interview, this diary spans two years of Willits time spent as Director of Social Sciences of the Rockefeller Foundation. The interviews are with various professionals in the field and the topics of conversation include discussions of various projects, grant proposals and fellowships that RF may contribute resources towards. Some of the topics discussed in the journal include implications of war funding, unemployment, labor studies, urban decay, agricultural science, impact of technology and public administration.
    World War II; Diaries; Labor; United States; Social sciences
  - 1944-1946, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 107)
    Scope and Content note
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits goes to the Southern United States to survey various southern schools. He interviews members of the college faculty and determines which departments are the strongest. The schools surveyed include University of Virginia, University of North Carolina, Duke University, North Carolina State College and North Carolina College for Negroes. Topics covered in this diary include rural poverty, black studies, populations, and World War II. Included in the diary are copies of "Subject Index to Joseph H. Willits ' Dixie Diary", "Racial Relationships in North Carolina", "Farm Labor Shortages and Maximum Production", "Agricultural Interests of Nonfarm Rural Leaders", "Twenty Years of Migration From Farms" and "Rural Industrialization Creates New Problems".
    Agriculture; Rural population; African Americans; United States; World War II
  - 1950, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry (Reel M Wil 1, Frame 332, Box 523)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits communicates with various professionals in the field and discusses rebuilding Germany and education during his travels to Germany and Switzerland. Various grant fellowship proposals and surveys are also discussed.
    Education; Germany; Switzerland
  - 1951 January-May, Willits, Joseph Henry; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 374)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this journal include political behavior, economics and economic history, and international relations. Princeton University's Institute of International Studies is discussed. Willits visits University of Pennsylvania to survey their social science department and attends a conference on Quantitative Description of Technological Change.
    United States; Statistics; Sociology; Economics; History; Anthropology; Population; Psychology; International relations; Political science; Social Science Research Council
  - 1951 June-December, DeVinney, Leland C.; Grant, John B.; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 529)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this journal include political behavior, economics and economic history, and international relations. Willits surveys British universities social sciences programs.
    Anthropology; Political science; International relations; England; Economics; United States; Sociology; Scotland
  - 1952 January-June, Willits, Joseph Henry; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 678)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this diary include functioning and management of the economy, human behavior, international relations, and moral and social philosophy.
    Political science; Social sciences; United States; Anthropology; Philosophy and religion; Law; International relations; Economics; Social Science Research Council
  - 1952 July-December, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 800)
    Scope and Contentsn note
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this diary include functioning and management of the economy, human behavior, international relations, and moral and social philosophy. Willits visits University of Basle to survey their RF funded Monetary and Credit Economics research.
    Economics; International relations; Law; Philosophy and religion; Anthropology; Political science; Social sciences; Switzerland; United States
  - 1953 January-June, Social Science Research Council; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 916)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this diary include functioning and management of the economy, human behavior, international relations, and moral and social philosophy. The area studies program of the Royal Institute of International Affairs and the Law School at University of Wisconsin are featured in this diary.
    United States; Social sciences; Methodology; Law; Political science; Philosophy and religion; Anthropology; Economics; Human behavior; International relations
  - 1953 July-December, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry; Social Science Research Council (Reel M Wil 1, Frame 1,091, Box 524)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this diary include functioning and management of the economy, human behavior, international relations, and moral and social philosophy. A study of the resources of South Africa is discussed, the Food Research Institute of Stanford University is surveyed and a trip to Berkeley, California is taken.
    Economics; Anthropology; Political science; Philosophy and religion; United States; Social sciences; International relations; Human behavior; Methodology; Law
  - 1954 January-June, Willits, Joseph Henry; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences (Box 524, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 1263)
  - Exhibits, 1943-1946; Willits, Joseph Henry; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences
    United States; Social sciences
- Wilson, David B.
  - 1932 January-May (Box 525)
  - 1932 June-December (Box 525)
  - 1934 (Box 525)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 525)
  - 1939-1941 (Box 526)
  - 1940, 1944, 1948, 1950-1951 (Box 526)
- Winegar, Elizabeth A.
  - 1961-1962 (Box 526)
  - 1963 (Box 526)
- Wing, Wilson Mumford
  - 1947-1948 (Box 526)
- Wood, Peter H.
  - 1971-1972 (Box 527)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 527)
- Work, Telford Hindley
  - 1953-1956 (Box 527)
- Worth, C. Brooke
  Mexico; Philippines
  - 1947-1953 (Box 527)
- Wortman, L. Sterling
  - 1966 January-May (Box 528)
  - 1966 June-December (Box 528)
  - 1967 (Box 528)
  - 1968 (Box 529)
  - 1969 (Box 529)
  - 1970 (Box 530)
  - 1971 (Box 530)
  - 1972 (Box 530)
  - 1973 (Box 531)
  - 1974 (Box 531)
  - 1975 (Box 531)
  - Index, 1966-1974 (Box 531)
- Wray, Joe D.
  - 1961 (Box 532)
  - 1962 (Box 532)
  - 1963 (Box 532)
  - 1964 (Box 532)
  - 1965-1968, 1971, 1973 (Box 532)
- Wright, Bill C.
  - 1968-1969 (Box 533)
- Wright, Christopher
  - 1972-1973 (Box 533)
- Young, Geoffrey Winthrop
  - 1929-1930 (Box 533)
- Yudelman, Montague
  - 1956 (Box 533)
  - 1957 (Box 534)
  - 1958 (Box 534)
  - 1959 (Box 535)
- Zinn, Earl F.
  - 1926-1927 (Box 535)